bearingpoint.com 2019-04-02

# Privacy Statement | BearingPoint

## Privacy and Cookie Statement

This Privacy Statement was last updated in May 2018 to reflect changes in data protection laws, specifically the GDPR . It sets out the data protection practices carried out through the use of the Internet and any other electronic communications networks by **BearingPoint Holding BV** and its associated companies (all together “ **BearingPoint** ”). A full list of our main offices can be found at  <https://www.bearingpoint.com/en/locations/>.

  * 1\. Personal Information Collected

1.1 BearingPoint collects personal information from you through the use of registration forms, for instance every time you sign up for an electronic newsletter, when you send us an application to be considered for employment, when you register for an event, when you submit a request for proposal or for information, when you request the authorization of downloading a document, when you enter an online competition or when you send us a message via an email reply mechanism provided on the BearingPoint sites.

  * 2\. Use of Personal Information

2.1 We process personal information collected via the BearingPoint sites for the purposes of:

    * Providing our services
    * Dealing with your enquiries and requests
    * Recruitment
    * Proposing/inviting access to BearingPoint’s social media accounts
    * Proposing/inviting to informational events and conferences
    * Providing you with information about products and services.

  * 3\. Information We Gather Automatically and How We Use It

3.1 When you visit one of the BearingPoint sites, we collect information automatically about those visits.

3.2 In particular, your browser automatically sends us certain Internet-related information, such as the Internet Protocol (IP) address of the computer you are using.

3.3 We also collect information through the use of cookies to better understand how visitors use the BearingPoint sites, to identify problems with our servers, prepare aggregate demographic information and other information regarding the use of the BearingPoint sites, and to improve the functions of the BearingPoint sites. Cookies do not collect any information that enables you to be identified as an individual.

  * 4\. Use of Cookies

4.1 Cookies are small text files that Web sites often store on computer hard drives of visitors to their sites. They are widely used in order to make Web sites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site.

4.2 A cookie contains a unique number, which is used to recognize your computer when a user of your computer returns to a Web site that it visited previously. We use cookies to enhance the online experience of our visitors, for statistical purposes and to better understand how our sites are used. Cookies may tell us, for example, whether you have visited our sites before or whether you are a new visitor.

4.3 There are two broad categories of cookies – ‘first party cookies’ and ‘third party cookies’. First party cookies are cookies that are served directly by the Web site operator to your computer, and are used only by the Web site operator to recognise your computer when it revisits that site. Third party cookies are served by a service provider on behalf of the Web site operator, and can be used by the service provider to recognise your computer when it visits other Web sites. Third party cookies are most commonly used for Web site analytics or advertising purposes.

4.4 This Web site serves only the following first party cookies to your computer:

**Cookie** | **Name** | **Purpose** | **More information**  
---|---|---|---  
Session cookies | JSESSIONID  
bpsession | These cookies are used to keep track of the session to know how many users are viewing the sites and to enable communication with the users’ Internet browsers. |    
Preference cookies | country  
locale | These cookies are used to hold information about the specific country site users are visiting and users’ language preference. |    
Google Analytics | _utma  
_utmb  
_utmc  
_utmz  
_utmv | These cookies are set by Google, Inc. and are used to collect information about how visitors use our sites. We use this information to compile reports and to help us improve the sites. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the sites, where visitors have come to the sites from and the pages they visited. | To see an overview of privacy at Google and how this applies to Google Analytics, visit 

[http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/  
privacy.html](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html).

To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.  
  
Google Optimize | _gaexp | Used to determine a user's inclusion in an experiment and the expiry of experiments a user has been included in. | 

To see an overview of privacy at Google and how this applies to Google Analytics, visit

[http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/  
privacy.html](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html).

To opt out of being tracked by Google Optimize across all websites visit <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.  
  
4.5 This website uses Hotjar, an analysis software from der Hotjar Ltd. („Hotjar“) ([https://www.hotjar.com](https://www.hotjar.com/), 3 Lyons Range, 20 Bisazza Street, Sliema SLM 1640, Malta, Europe). Hotjar makes it possible to measure and analyse user behaviour (clicks, mouse movements, scrolling, etc.) on our website. The tracking code and cookie generate data about your visit to our website, which is then transmitted to the Hotjar server in Ireland and stored there. The tracking code collects the following data:

Device-dependent data

    * The IP address of your device (collected and stored in anonymised format)
    * Your email address, including your first and last name, if you have provided this information via our website
    * Your device’s screen size
    * Type of device and browser information
    * Geographic location (country only)
    * Your preferred language for using our website

Log data

    * Linking domain
    * Pages visited
    * Geographic location (country only)
    * Your preferred language for using our website
    * Date and time of website visit

Hotjar will use this information to analyse your use of our website, compile reports on usage, and provide further services connected with use of the website and the internet. To this end, Hotjar also uses the services of third parties such as Google Analytics and Optimizely. These third parties may store data that is sent by your browser when you visit the website, such as cookies or IP requests. Please consult the data privacy statements of Google Analytics and Optimizely for more information about how data is stored and used.

By using this website you declare your consent to the above-mentioned processing of the data collected by Hotjar and its third-party service providers as specified in their data privacy statements.

The cookies used by Hotjar have different lifetimes. Some may remain valid for up to 365 days while others expire after the current visit.

If you do not wish data to be collected by Hotjar, please click here and follow the instructions: <https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out>

4.6 Furthermore, when browsing the BearingPoint website you may get access to embedded media and other external sources which may store cookies. As cookies from externally embedded media may be used or modified without BearingPoint’s knowledge or consent, you are invited to consult the following links for further information.

4.7 You have the right to choose whether or not to accept cookies. You can exercise this right by amending or setting the controls on your browser to reflect your cookie preferences. However, please note that if you choose to refuse cookies you may not be able to use the full functionality of the BearingPoint sites.

4.8 The "help" portion of the toolbar on most Internet browsers will tell you how to change your browser cookie settings, including how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, and how to disable cookies altogether. For further information about cookies and how to control their use, please visit the following third party educational resources: [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

  * 5\. Information We Share

5.1 We will only disclose personal information to other companies within our group of companies, business partners, government bodies and law enforcement agencies, successors in title to our business and suppliers we engage to process data on our behalf. In these circumstances we will share your personal information for purposes such as our legitimate business purposes and to comply with legal obligations.

  * 6\. Links to Other Sites

6.1 This Privacy Statement applies only to information collected by a BearingPoint site.

6.2 BearingPoint sites contain links to other sites that are not owned or administered by BearingPoint. Please be aware that BearingPoint is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other third party sites. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of every Web site you visit.

  * 7\. Security

7.1 We maintain safeguards to protect against unauthorized disclosure, use, alteration, or destruction of the personal information you provide to us through the BearingPoint sites. Please note, however, that perfect security does not exist on the Internet. Therefore, while we endeavour to protect your personal data, when data is transferred over the Internet it may potentially be accessed and used by unauthorised parties.

  * 8\. Access and Correction and Deletion

8.1 We want to make sure that any information we hold on you is up to date and correct. You can request from BearingPoint information as to your personal data held by us as a controller, the purpose of the storage and obtain certain other information about how and why we process your personal data. Furthermore, and within the legal framework, you have the right to request for your personal data to be amended or rectified where it is inaccurate, the right to restrict our processing of your personal data and the right to obtain deletion of your personal data. If you have any requests concerning your personal information BearingPoint holds about you , to obtain a copy or any queries with regard to these practices please contact us at the contact listed below:

BearingPoint Data Protection Departement  
Group Compliance Officer  
BearingPoint Berlin  
Kurfürstendamm 207-208  
10719 Berlin  
Fax: +49 30- 880041040

  * 9\. Internet-based Transfers

9.1 Given that the Internet is a global environment, using the Internet to collect and process personal data necessarily involves the transmission of data on an international basis. Therefore, by browsing the BearingPoint sites and communicating electronically with us, you acknowledge our processing of personal data in this way. However, we will endeavour to protect all personal information collected through the BearingPoint sites in accordance with strict data protection standards.

  * 10\. Changes to the Privacy Statement

We reserve the right to amend this Statement at any time without advance notice in order to address future developments of BearingPoint, the Website or changes in industry or legal trends. We will post the revised Statement on the Website or announce the change on the home page of the Website. You can determine when the Statement was revised by referring to the "Last Updated" date on the top of this Statement. Any changes will become effective upon the posting of the revised Statement on the Website. By continuing to use the Website following such changes, you will be deemed to have agreed to such changes. If you do not agree with the terms of this Statement, in whole or part, you can choose to not continue to use the Website. 

  * 11\. Contact Us

If you have any general questions or concerns about how we  process personal information please contact us at  [privacy@bearingpoint.com](mailto:privacy@bearingpoint.com)
